Kheel, Theodore W. Newspaper Clipping File 6021/009
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Theodore W. Kheel Newspaper Clipping File
1968-1995
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Kheel, Theodore W.
6021/009
6 cubic feet
6 linear ft.
Clippings (information artifacts).
8240976
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
C. Westerman, May 01, 2014
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, August 13, 2015
Biographical / Historical
Theodore Woodrow Kheel was said to be named for both Woodrow Wilson and his political rival Theodore Roosevelt, the result of a compromise between his politically differing parents. The settlement presaged a career in which Kheel would be tapped by mayors, governors, and presidents to settle disputes that were part of the nation's major political and social transitions from post-World War II to well into the 21st century.
Born in 1914 in Brooklyn, Ted Kheel attended public high school in the Bronx. He was awarded a Regents scholarship to Cornell University, where he attended an accelerated undergraduate law school program permitting him to earn a bachelor's and law degree in six years.
In private practice for a brief time after graduation from law school, Kheel soon was offered a position as a National Labor Relations Board attorney in Washington. Kheel's special talents as a mediator and his obvious political skills soon gave him the opportunity to move to a new war-time agency, where he was initially hired as principal mediation officer. By 1944, he had been appointed executive director of the National War Labor Board, with a staff of 2,500 who were hearing 150 disputes a week. Kheel's work at the WLB introduced him to the most important figures in the labor movement and key government officialscontacts he would use effectively in the future.
Following the end of World War II, Kheel returned to New York City and was drafted by Mayor O'Dywer to serve in the city's new Labor Relations Division, which Kheel came to head within a year. With the agreement of the mayor, Kheel was able to serve both in this position and maintain a separate, private law practice.
In 1949, Kheel was appointed to a part-time position as impartial chairman for an important segment of public transit in New York City, a position in which he would render 30,000 decisions through 1982. Also in 1949, Kheel became a partner in the New York law firm Battle, Fowler, Jaffin and Kheel. His skills in conflict resolution led an observer to remark that the firm's work began with a battle, ended by Kheel.
During his more than half a century of involvement in labor matters, Kheel was known above all else for his extraordinary ability to get feuding parties to make concessions to reach an agreement. In the important New York and national labor disputes which he would be called to mediate, Kheel's approach was to protect management rights and at the same time demand fairness to workers while also trying to protect the public interest in the issue.
Kheel's was frequently the voice of reason in settling a number of extremely difficult labor disputes of the 1960s and 1970s. Mayor Robert F. Wagner, Jr., turned to Kheel to help end the 114-day newspaper strike of 1962-63. Among his most infamous cases was the strike involving Mike Quill, head of the Transport Workers Union, who publically battled Mayor John V. Lindsay in 1965-66. Kheel's efforts also included helping coordinate bargainers and mediators during the 35-day New York City teachers' strike in 1968. President Lyndon B. Johnson summoned Kheel to Washington in 1964 to help mediate 10 days of feverish negotiations that prevented a nationwide rail walkout. Kheel would ultimately serve as a mediator and advisor for virtually every New York mayor from O'Dwyer to Beame, for the Kennedy-Johnson Administration, and other presidential administrations as well.
Kheel's interests in public issues were not limited to the labor sector. The policy disputes that came to his attention as a mediator and lawyer frequently cried out for larger solutions, and Kheel was not averse to using his considerable public presence and media contacts to seek redress, especially for what he viewed as past institutional injustices or misguided government actions. Although pressed to do so on a number of occasions, Kheel refused to run for elective office, preferring the role of a labor neutral and public advocate.
Kheel was also not averse to backing his powers of persuasion with legal action: a fierce advocate for public transit, he initiated a class action lawsuit over the Port Authority of New York and New Jersey's refusal to fund mass rail transit. His most sustained crusade for the public good related to his battle to limit commuter auto traffic and control highway building in New York City in favor of increased use of public transportation. Initially attacked by Port Authority officials and some city, state, and federal politicians of both parties, many of the solutions originally proposed by Kheel, including the concept of the subsidized fare, became public policy in later years.
An early supporter of the civil rights movement, Kheel and his wife Ann become involved with the New York Urban League in the 1950s. He served as its president in 1955 and as national president for four years. He worked with President Johnson on race issues and with Martin Luther King, Jr., in a libel suit against the New York Times. Kheel's mediation skills led to important strides in hiring African Americans in the airline industry. His reputation for sensitivity to minority issues resulted in his becoming involved in efforts to add civilians to the New York City Police Review Board in 1965. Kheel was also recruited as a peacemaker in the 1968 Ocean Hill-Brownsville Teachers dispute.
Even though Kheel handled disputes for transit workers, typesetters, and longshoremen, he reveled in the finer things in life, and dabbled as a restaurateur in fine food and was a patron of the fine arts.
He once owned a stake in Le Pavillon, a leading French restaurant in Manhattan, among others. He also represented numerous artists, including Robert Rauschenberg and Christo, and was the prime mover in the realization of the long-heralded Gates Project in Central Park in 2005.
He also made millions of dollars as an entrepreneur while facilitating sustainable economic and social change. He was the lead investor in the giant Punta Cana resort, transforming 30 miles of jungle in the Dominican Republic, and helped bring about the airport that opened that country to tourists and travelers.
Finding the solution to problems such as the impact of automation on the workplace, community disputes, and protecting a sustainable environment in which mankind will flourish, to name but a few, were the focus of Kheel's interest, enthusiasm, and financial support. He was the prime mover, bringing along like-minded citizens and specialists, in the creation of organizations to find solutions to the more intractable issues facing society. The Foundation on Employee Health, Medical Care and Welfare, the Foundation on Automation and Employment (and its British counterpart), Automation House, the Institute for Mediation and Conflict Resolution, and the Earth Pledge Foundation were among the most successful of such efforts. In the same vein, in collaboration with Price, Waterhouse in 1994, Kheel formed Prevention and Early Resolution of Conflicts, Inc. (PERC), now housed at Cornell ILR as Cornell/PERC Institute.
A prolific writer, Kheel is perhaps best known for his encyclopedic work on labor law. Throughout a career that was active almost until his death at age 96 in November 2010, he was able to balance, with amazing success, advocacy of the public good and the management of a successful law and mediation practice and other business and cultural interests.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5024: Theodore W. Kheel Arbitration Awards 5776 AV: Theodore W. Kheel Interviews and Programs 6017: Theodore W. Kheel Newspaper Clipping File 6021 AV: Theodore W. Kheel Audio-Visual Materials 6021 MB: Theodore W. Kheel Memorabilia 6021 P: Theodore W. Kheel Photographs 6021/001: Theodore W. Kheel Correspondence 6021/003: Theodore W. Kheel Arbitration files 6021/004: Theodore W. Kheel Legal Files 6021/005: Theodore W. Kheel Speeches and Articles 6021/006: Theodore W. Kheel Non-Profit Organization Files 6021/007: Theodore W. Kheel Subject Files 6021/008: Theodore W. Kheel Books and Articles 6021/010: Theodore W. Kheel Additional Files 6021/011: Theodore W. Kheel Punta Cana Files 6021/012m: Invitation and Program for the Theodore W. Kheel Memorial Service 6059 OH: Thomas Shactman Interviews with Theodore W. Kheel 6194 OH: College of Labor and Employment Lawyers Interview with Theodore W. Kheel 6196 OH: New York City Central Labor Council Interview of Theodore W. Kheel for Central Archives 6207 OH: CLEL Video Oral History Project
Kheel, Theodore Woodrow
8240976
- Chronological Index. Pages 1-127., 1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  September 1995
- Chronological Index. Pages 128-261., 1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Volume 1: Corrected Index, Affinity Group Credit Cards, American Foundation on Automation and Employment. American Labor Movement., 1951-1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Volume 1: America Labor Movement, Arbitrations: AAU/NCAA, Brewery Industry, Civil Rights, Entertainment Industry, 1970-1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Volume 1. Arbitrations: Maritime, Milk Industry, Newspaper and Printing Industries, Pocketbook Workers Union, Leather Goods, Rubber Industry, 1949-1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Volume 1. Arbitrations: Teamsters, Transit., 1953-1984 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Volume 2. Center for Non-Broadcast Television, Christo's Gates Project, Civil Rights: Kheel Articles and Statements, Kheel Booklet and Book on EEO., 1956-1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Civil Rights: New York and National Urban League, National Urban League, Ghana Air.
- Volume 2: Arbitration, Automation House, 1967-1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Volume 2: Civil Rights., 1958-1964 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  National Urban League, Electrical Workers Union, Gandhi Society, Alabama Libel Suits, Sullivan vs. NY Times, Press Communication EEO Kheel Report, Mayors Committee on Job Advance, Apprentice Plan, Local No. 6 Typographical Union.
- Volume 2. Civil Rights: Minority Hiring by NYC, Columbia University Campus Demonstrations, Composers and Lyricists Guild vs. TV and Movie Producers, Conflict Resolution, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Volume 2. Conflict Resolution: Attica, Board of Mediation of Community Disputes., 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Volume 3. Electrical Industry, Experiments in Art and Technology, Clay Felker NY Magazine, Foundation of Employee Health, Medical Care, David Graiver, Hospital Strikes, 1959-1977 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Volume 3. Industrial and Labor Relations: Air Transport, Alternatives to Strike, Arbitration, Schelling's Essay, Collective Bargaining, 1946- 1963 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Volume 3. Industrial and Labor Relations: Collective Bargaining, Mediation, 1964-1980 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Volume 3. Industrial and Labor Relations: Public Sector Bargaining, Taylor Law, Public Sector, Strikes, Kheel Report to Speaker Travia., 1968- 1993 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Volume 3. Institute for Collective Bargaining and Group Relations, Kheel Awards and Honors., 1948-1987 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Volume 4. Kheel: Awards and Honors, Biographical Materials., 1943-1991 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Volume 4. Kheel Biographical Materials., 1968-1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Volume 4. Kheel: Favorable Media and Comments, Gilbane Housing, Litigation as Counsel, Litigation as Party., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Volume 4. Kheel's Relations with Media, John vs. Lindsay as Mayor, Local No. 6 International Typographical Union, MARC, MGM Proxy Fight, 1966-1975 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Volume 4. Kheel: Biographical Materials, Corporate Directorship Offices and Investments, Favorable Media and Comments, 1947- 1993 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Volume 5. Maritime Industry, 1957-1965 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  1957-1959; July 2 1962 - July 13 1963; August 10 - October 26 1963; November 2 1963 - June 20 1964; August 3 - December 23 1964; 1965
- Volume 5. Maritime Industry, Milk Driver Disputes and Strikes, Municipal Government Service, Non-Transit, 1948-1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Volume 5. Municipal Government Service, Report of the Mayor's Transit Advisory Committee., 1946-1948 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  September 9 1946 - December 27 1948
- Volume 5. Municipal Government Service, Transit, National Football League, 1946-1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Volume 6. New York City and State Politics, 1946-1978 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  1946-1967; 1968-1978
- Volume 6. New York City and State Politics: 1982 Gubernatorial Race, Kheel vs. Koch. New York City Development and Economic Data., 1947- 1989 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Volume 6. Kheel as Impartial Arbitrator, New York City Governmental Process and Structure, Kheel Articles, New York Private Transit, 1949- 1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Volume 6. New York City: Mayor's Fact-Finding and Mediation Boards, Bus Strikes and Threats., 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  June 6 - July 20 1949, July 21 - November 9 1949; May 25 - December 29 1950
- Volume 6. New York City Bus Strikes and Threats, 1951-1960 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  November and December 1951; January 1952 - December 1953; 1954-1960
- Volume 7. New York City Subway, Bus Strikes and Threats, 1961-1964 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  1961; 1962; 1963-1964
- Volume 7. New York City Subway and Bus Strikes., 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  July 27 - December 24 1965; December 25 1965 - January 5 1966; January 6 - January 11 1966.
- Volume 7. New York City Subway and Bus Strike and Threats., 1966-1979 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  January 12 - 26 1966; 1967; 1969; 1971; 1973-1979
- Volume 7. New York City Subway and Bus Strike and Threats, Metropolitan Transit Authority, NY Magazine Rupert Murdoch Controversy, NY Post, NY Times, Newspaper Disputes and Strikes, 1963-1981 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Volume7. Newspaper Disputes and Strikes, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  March 30 - June 27 1965; June 30 - September 18 1965; September 18 - 24 1965
- Volume 7. Newspaper Disputes and Strikes., 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  September 25 - October 9 1965; October 10 - November 16 1965; 1966
- Volume 8. Newspaper Disputes and Strikes., 1967-1970 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  March 11 - April 1 1967; April 1 - 30 1967; May 1 - November 6 1967; 1968; March 24 - April 20 1970
- Volume 8. Newspaper Disputes and Strikes, 1970-1977 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  April 21 - May 27 1970. June 27 - November 10 1970; 1973; 1974; 1975-1977
- Volume 8. Newspaper Disputes and Strikes, Newspaper Issues: Possible Sale of New York News, 1978-1982 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  September 1 - 30 1978; October 2 - 31 1978; November 6 1978 - April 27 1979; 1081-1982, April 5 - May 25 1982
- Volume 8. Newspapers: Disputes and Strikes at NY News and NY Post, Issues in Possible Sales of Amsterdam News and NY Post, 1983- 1990 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  May 1983; 1988; January 22 - July 31 1990; August 2 - November 20 1990; November 20 - December 24 1990
- Volume 8. Daily News Strike, Kheel and Freeman Manuscript, Daily News Strike, Chronology of Key Events, Daily News Strike and Sale, 1990- 1991 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Volume 9. Pennsylvania State University Controversy, Samuel R Pierce, Jr., Plumbing Industry, Police Disputes and Strikes, Police Review Board, Punta Cana Beach Resort, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Volume 9. Queens College Controversy, Railroad Disputes and Strikes, Republic National Bank, Sanitation Workers Disputes and Strikes, PL Roy Siemiller, Stirling Homex Corp., 1964-1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Volume 9. Disputes and Strikes: Taxi Drivers, Teachers, 1963-1967 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Volume 9. Teachers Disputes and Strikes: Ocean Hill. Transit Fares and Tolls., 1955-1975 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Volume 9. Transit Fares and Tolls, Transit Workers Unions, Transportation Bond Issue, 1969-1978 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Volume 10. Transportation Bond Issue, Railroad Bond Issue, Transportation Policy, 1955-1974 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Volume 10. Transportation Policy, Port of NY Authority, 1965-1973 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Volume 10. Transportation Policy Port of New York Authority, United Nations, UNRIO 1992 Earth Pledge and Summit, UN Conferences in Cairo and Vienna, 1973-1994 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Volume 10. Vietnam War Paris Peace Talks, Wage Stabilization: Korean War, Nixon 1971 Program, World War II, Robert F Wagner, 1941- 1971 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Volume 10. War Labor Board, Westside Convention Center, Westside Highway, Western Union, World Trade Center, Whitney M Young, Jr., 1942-1974 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Volume 2 Duplicate Copy. Automation, Automation House, Center for Non-Broadcast Television, Christo's Gates Projects, 1967- 1976 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Volume 2 Duplicate Copy. Civil Rights: Kheel Articles and Speeches, Kheel Booklet and Book on EEO, National Urban League, 1956- 1965 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Volume 2 Duplicate Copy. Civil Rights: National Urban League, Electrical Workers, Gandhi Society, Alabama Libel Suits, Sullivan vs. Times, President's Committee on EEO, Apprenticeship Plan, 1960-1974 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Volume 2 Duplicate Copy. Composers and Lyricists Guild vs. TV Movie Producers, Columbia University Campus, Conflict Resolutions: General, Attica, Board of Mediation of Community Disputes, Institute for Mediation, 1968-1972 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Volume 3 Duplicate Copy. Electrical Industry, Experiments in Art and Technology, NY Magazine and Village Voice, Foundation on Employee Health Medical Care, David Graiver, Industrial and Labor Relations, 1946-1979 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  Spanish and English
- Volume 3 Duplicate Copy. Industrial and Labor Relations: Arbitration, Collective Bargaining, Schelling's Essay, 1946-1969 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Volume 3 Duplicate Copy. Industrial and Labor Relations: Collective Bargaining, Mediation, Public Sector and the Taylor Law, Strikes, 1968- 1993 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Volume 3 Duplicate Copy. Industrial and Labor Relations: Taylor Law and Kheel Report Trivia, Institute of Collective Bargaining and Group Relations, Kheel Awards Honors and Special Recognitions, 1948-1987 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Volume 8 Duplicate Copy. Newspaper Disputes and Strikes, 1967-1970 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  March 11 - April 1 1967; April 1 - 30 1967, May 1 - November 6 1967; 1968; March 24 - April 20 1970; April 21 - May 27 1970
- Volume 8. Newspaper Disputes and Strikes., 1970-1978 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  June 27 - November 10 1970; 1973; 1974; 1975-1977; September 1 - 30 1978; October 1 - 30 1978
- Volume 8 Duplicate Copy. Newspaper Disputes and Strikes, Possible Sales of NY Daily News and Amsterdam News, Sale of NY Post, 1978- 1990 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  November 6 1978 - April 27 1979; 1981-1982; April 5 - May 25 1982; 1983; 1988; January 22 - July 31 1990
- Volume 8 Duplicate Copy. Newspaper Disputes and Strikes: NY Daily News, New York Post, Kheel-Freeman (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Volume 8 Duplicate Copy. New York Daily News Strike: Chronology of Events and Sale, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Volume 10 Duplicate Copy. Transportation Bond Issue, Railroad Preservation Board, Transportation Policy, Port Authority of New York, 1955- 1974 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Volume 10 Duplicate Copy. Transportation Policy: New York Port Authority., 1962-1977 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Volume 10 Duplicate Copy. United Nations, UN Rio Conference: Earth Pledge, Vienna, Cairo. Vietnam War Paris Peace Talks, Wage Stabilization: Korean War, Nixon Program, 1971-1994 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Volume 10 Duplicate Copy. World War II Wage Stabilization, Robert F Wagner, War Labor Board, Westside Convention Center, Western Union, World Trade Center, Whitney M Young, Jr., 1941-1974 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous Clippings, 1964-1979 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- New York City News Clips, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- St. John's Journal. St. John's Affiliates with CNB-TV, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  July 15 1983
- St. John's Press Release and Clippings (Box 5, Folder 4)
- AFL-CIO Newspaper Clippings for Legal Fee Insurance, 1967-1975 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Transportation Bond Issue Newspaper Clippings, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Highway Action Coalition Newspaper Clippings, 1971-1974 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous New York Labor Newspaper Clippings, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Kheel New York Labor Newspaper Clippings, 1966-1974 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Transportation Newspaper Clippings and Data, 1964-1975 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Newspaper Clippings Regarding Theodore Kheel, 1966-1974 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Newspaper Clippings Concerning Kheel and Strikes, 1967-1974 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Daily News. Theodore W Kheel et al vs. Edward I Koch et al. Newspaper Clippings, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings. Theodore Kheel et al vs. Edward Koch et al., 1981 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Village Voice. Theodore Kheel vs. Edward Koch., 1981 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  June 1981
- Urban Development Corp. Newspaper Clippings and Releases, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Newspaper Clippings Concerning Paper Strikes and Effects of Automation, 1961-1974 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Kheel on Transportation. Newspaper Clippings and Articles. Volume 1., 1955-1971 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Theodore Kheel on Transportation. Newspaper Clippings. Volume 1., 1955-1970 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  1955 - June 12 1970
- The New York Knickerbocker., 1968 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  May 26 1968
- Volume 6. New York City and New York State Politics, 1946-1967 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Volume 6. New York City and New York State Politics., 1968-1978 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Volume 6. New York City and New York State Politics., 1982 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Volume 6. New York City and New York State Politics. Mayoral Race Kheel vs. Koch., 1981-1989 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Volume 6. New York City Development and Economic Data, 1947-1965 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Volume 6. New York City Development and Economic Data., 1966-1979 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Volume 6. New York City Development and Economic Data. Ehrenhalt Reports., 1993 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Volume 6. New York City Governmental Process and Structure, Kheel Articles, 1952-1983 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Volume 6. New York City Private Transit. Buses., 1949-1955 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Volume 6. New York City Transit Authority and the Transit Workers Union, 1954-1982 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Volume 6. New York City Transit. Mayor's Fact Finding., 1946-1969 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Volume 6. New York City Bus Strikes and Threats., 1949 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  June 6 - July 20 1949
- Volume 6. New York City Bus Strikes and Threats., 1949 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  July 21 - November 29 1949
- Volume 6. New York City Bus Strikes and Threats., 1950 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  May 25 - December 29 1950
- Volume 6. New York City Bus Strikes and Threats., 1951 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  November 1951
- Volume 6. New York City Bus Strikes and Threats., 1951 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  December 1951
- Volume 6. New York City Bus Strikes and Threats., 1952-1953 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  January 1952 - December 1953
- Volume 6. New York City Bus Strikes and Threats., 1954-1960 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Volume 7. New York City Bus and Subway Strike and Threats, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Volume 7. New York City Bus and Subway Strike and Threats, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Volume 7. New York City Bus and Subway Strikes and Threats, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Volume 7. New York City Bus and Subway Strikes and Threats., 1965 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  July 27 - December 24 1965